Podcasting 2.0 for July 16th, 2021,
episode 46. We're sliding into your PMs.
Still can't believe I get to
do this every single week.
Ladies and gentlemen,
welcome once again to the important
meeting for Podcasting 2.0.
Everything going on at
podcastindex.org, podcastindex.social.
It is Friday once again.
I'm Adam Curry here in the heart of
Hill Country, Texas, and in Alabama.
The man who shows up in my PMs, my friend
on the other end, Dave Jones, everybody.
I was listening to DH Unplugged. That's my
Friday morning, get ready for podcasting.
Oh, yeah, I can't listen to it anymore.
Why?
Because it doesn't work
on the apps that I like.
Oh, yeah, that's right. Well,
there's that one problem.
There's that one, and it really hurts.
You know, I was like, yeah, I can
go to the website and hit play,
but it's not the same thing, so I'm going
to have to get in Horwitz's face again.
Yeah, I like that podcast because Horwitz,
he's such a good podcaster, man. He has a
great delivery. Yeah. It's just great, and
so it gets me all fired up, but they were
talking about movies, and I miss movies.
I miss going to the movie theater.
Going to the movies? Oh, really? Yeah.
I've never been a movie
theater guy at all.
I just, you know, we watched
that new movie with Chris Pratt.
Oh, oh, that's not, that's supposed
to be pretty good. What's it called?
No, no. Oh, it's not good?
Oh, it's awful.
What movie is it?
It's called The Tomorrow War, I think.
Oh, you know what it is?
A lot of No Agenda producers have
been telling me to watch it because
there's, they say, it's great.
Tomorrow War, it's like we're
fighting the, whatever we're
fighting, and it's all social justice
warrior stuff throughout the entire movie.
Oh, I don't, no, I didn't
really pick that up.
Oh, okay. Well, it's No Agenda
people are very sensitive.
Oh, they are, yes, yes.
But, I mean, like, no, this is the
worst pile of steaming garbage.
Oh, goodness.
Do not waste your time.
I mean, what are you
going to tell me next,
that the new Marky Mark
movie is no good, too?
I mean, that's going to crush me.
Is there a new Marky Mark?
Yeah, Mark Wahlberg has a new movie.
I like Mark Wahlberg.
I toured with him.
I like him.
Oh, I don't know anything
about Mark Wahlberg.
He's never been on my radar screen.
He's like just one of those guys that's
just floating around in the periphery.
If I happen to see a
movie with him on, I'm like, nah, okay.
All right. Anyway, I'm sorry.
I interrupted your flow.
Okay.
No, it is indicative of lower budget.
We can get away with just throwing a bunch
of cliches at a script, roll it
out, and people will watch it.
I mean, it's just, oh, it's so bad.
There will never be another
Schindler's List made.
Never.
I just don't think so.
Hmm. And is that the movie you go to when
you're talking about, is that your go-to
best movie ever, or?
No, that wouldn't be the go-to.
I would just say, like, it's an
example of a, oh, here's another one.
I would say there would never be
another, what was that movie from a few
years ago that they had, it was
like a war, a future time when men,
where everybody was sterile and
nobody could give birth anymore.
Oh, Handmaid's Tale?
No, no, no, no, no.
This is like, it's like a war-torn
thing, and they're trying to get
this kid through there. It
was like a serious flick.
I really don't know.
Oh, yeah.
I'm not a movie buff.
But anyway, it was, I mean, like, these,
these, like, epics of cinema, they just,
I don't see how they
could be made anymore.
Oh, well, sure.
I mean, it's, it's the same with
music, although there's always valiant
efforts, but once we went from
CD to MP3, it's like, all right,
that's what we're used to now.
Yeah.
Is there ever, there will
never be another, you know,
news of the world or something like
that level, you know, album?
Oh, oh, oh, no.
Well, it's, it's not going to, even
vinyl, you know, vinyl has certain
compression that takes place,
and it's your audio chain.
I used to be an audiophile.
We all had the tube amps, the Morantz, you
know, we had the Techniques Turntable,
have a Revox reel-to-reel, mmm,
baby, oh, hold on a second.
Mr. Adam Curry.
Open up the door, Mr. Curry, now!
I'm sorry.
I, I stupidly left the door
closed to the board room.
I'm going to get everybody
in here. Everybody in? All the developers?
Oh, nice.
They're here, they're here,
they're here, they're here.
Box lunches on the table.
The cookies are stale.
I have a question for you.
Since we've been doing this
show, let's see, it was probably
a year ago this time that I was bored in
the house, and I'm in the house bored,
and we started working on understanding
the Lightning Network, so we've,
a lot has happened in that year.
How's Clubhouse doing with that
great podcast integration?
Is Clubhouse, does it still exist?
Exactly.
You remember how everyone was going, oh,
Clubhouse, oh, we're all going to be on
Clubhouse, all right, over there,
we'll pick you up on Clubhouse,
we're doing live on Clubhouse.
And I think I was skeptical
from the beginning.
Yeah, I think you were.
Skeptical is an understatement.
And it kind of ties into history,
not necessarily repeating, but boy,
is it rhyming with the
RSS conversation again.
This week was the tale
of two articles, really.
I mean, if you want to think about
it, because you had an excellent,
wonderful article about
saving, about how podcasters need
to save the medium from Evoterra.
Great article.
And then, like, eight hours later, you had
RSS is junk, Spotify is the way forward.
Yeah.
I mean, like, I've never seen such a
whipsaw from one extreme to another before.
Well, I think it was really two different
conversations about two different things.
The way I read Evoterra's post, which
I'll link in the show notes, was,
you know, the namespace,
namespace 2.0, all these
features that have popped up,
which I think you and I were quite
surprised by that as well.
It's like, you know, we thought, that
was great, we'll have a namespace,
there's a transcript,
there's a couple things people want,
we're going to put the value block in.
And for, wow, for months and months,
the value block was, although working,
was on the back
burner for everybody, and just all
these features started popping up.
And I think that's what
Evoterra was pointing at more.
And as I listened to the new
media show with Todd and Rob,
with Tanner Campbell, that seemed
to be only about making money.
And the only person who
even has a little bit
of experience with the value
for value model is Todd.
You know, I don't think the consultant
Campbell had even tried it.
But it seemed that that's
all they were talking about,
was discoverability and monetization.
And it kind of dawned on me, I
understand where people come from.
Like, yeah, with YouTube, the algo will
pick up on trend or what people like,
and it connects people.
And if there's an audience for
that particular video, actually,
not even for a channel or a
consistent podcast, so-called podcast,
the algo whips that up, you know,
and it gives you an audience.
And then once you have, you've reached a
threshold, you can start making some money.
And then there's, you know, there's,
so it's discoverability is kind of
built into the monetization mechanism.
With RSS, it's completely
decoupled from that.
It's two different things.
And, you know, the, it's just, oh man, the
constant monetization, making money, man.
I was like, oh, it's not
really always about that.
It can also just be about
an enriching experience.
That's what the namespace
is really bringing.
So it was, and I was surprised.
I thought there would be, to me,
because podcasting 2.0 came
up in that conversation.
And, you know, it's like, oh no,
I'm focused on creators, creators.
Well, this is, podcasting
2.0 is for creators.
Forget the value for value
streaming payments for a second.
Just look at what you can do with
transcripts, with chapters, with clips, with,
or soundbites,
with a trailer, with geolocation,
person, et cetera, et cetera, et cetera.
That's, that's the stuff creators
have really, really wanted.
So it was kind of like everyone was, you
know, just talking about different things.
And in the meantime,
I feel that a lot of
people who are talking may
not know much about
what's actually going on.
Yeah, I think there's
some of that for sure,
that the details have
gotten lost a little bit.
I think, to me, my whole, my whole issue,
my sort of foundational
issue with the whole debate
was that beta itself just
doesn't make any sense.
Because you're, it's billed as,
as like a RSS versus Spotify,
which is kind of like saying
HTTP versus Facebook.
I mean, it's a, one's a protocol, the other
one is a, is a platform or a service.
And so the whole argument doesn't,
doesn't really make any sense.
I mean, if you step back, if you,
if you step back and look at it,
what started the whole,
or how we got sort of roped
into the whole thing was with,
was Tanner had pointed out on Twitter,
to me that only 15% of the
podcasts in the index were,
were active in the last 60 days.
So you see this big number, 4 million,
and then you look down and you
see 600,000 podcasts, you know,
have been, have recently
published an episode.
And then, you know, then, then he went
on to sort of pimp, you know, Spotify.
But the, the problem is Spotify
and its subsidiary, Anchor,
are the ones that are responsible
for almost all of that garbage.
That's the funny part.
Yeah.
I mean, you know, literally, I've
got the, I've got the latest.
Oh, he's got stats.
He's got numbers.
He's showing up with a spreadsheet.
Anchor has 100, let's see, 1,667,977
podcasts in the podcast index.
So almost half, close to half of the
podcasts in the index are Anchor.
And of those, I can tell you that
only about 260,000 of those have had,
have published an episode
in anything close to what
you would call recent
within the last few months.
So the, the whole problem
of, if, if you want to bowl,
if you want to bowl discoverability down
to sheer math, a sheer numbers game,
then Anchor, Anchor slash Spotify
is the worst offender out there.
Yeah, good point.
By a large margin.
But, and, but, so there's kind of the
point is, so there's two conversations.
Let's put the monetization thing aside.
There's RSS or no RSS.
And the argument is always being made.
Well, you can do it better this way.
It's a richer format with this.
You know, it's a, it should be JSON.
It should be Atom.
It should be only Spotify.
It should be only behind the Apple.
Whatever it is, it's always
about RSS going away.
But the history, we need
to remember the history.
RSS was blogging.
It was micro blogging.
Then it added podcasting.
And Evan and Jack were very smart.
When they started Odeo, they were looking
at creating a full podcasting experience.
And they realized very quickly that
if you don't control the feeds,
if you don't control the distribution,
you're really not going to have a business.
So they took, and the first Twitter,
as far as I know, was RSS based.
You know, they had the
huge overhaul at one point
and fail wheels were just
going out of control.
Because guess what?
Aggregating RSS feeds is very hard.
It's not, you know, and so now there's this
huge platform and that no one monetizes
on, as far as I know.
You know, creators, except
for, you know, ancillary.
And it's a closed system.
They even kicked the developers out at
a certain point because they wanted to
control the experience.
And that's how they became a multi-billion
dollar company by closing it off and
having a walled garden.
They knew it couldn't work.
Google killed Google Reader to then
go and create, I think it was,
I don't know what it was.
Was that Google, was that Plus?
Was it Google Plus?
Was that Buzz?
Buzz, I think, first.
And that also didn't work.
So it's the idea that you're going to have
discoverability and monetization in one
or discoverability at all.
It's just a farce.
It's, that's also not how
it's worked traditionally.
It is, you bump into someone
and they listen to this.
It's a lot of word of mouth.
It's a lot of people who are
promoting on your behalf,
which I think is what I've learned
how to, to harness is the,
the power of, of producers.
You're seeing your audience as producers,
but all this other stuff is like,
holy crap, man, we're
still talking about this.
It won't go away.
It's, it's, it's like Bitcoin in a
way, you know, it's a honey badger.
Like, okay, whatever, step on me.
And, and I, and I thought Todd in particular
did a very good job defending his
position, but also not for
a second was he phased.
You know, he didn't get
frustrated, didn't get mad.
He had the right, I was
very impressed with that.
But I, but it kind of went
off the rails when all
it was about was podcasters
want to make money.
Well, you and I know that's not true.
In fact, we took a vow of poverty
to start this damn project.
Well, you know, I'll
say this about Tanner.
He was very kind to us in that
interview spoke, you know, he, his,
his basic thesis is that we're, that
we're just all wasting our time.
Yeah.
But, you know, he, he did say, you know,
like I said, he was kind about it.
He's like, Hey, I respect
everything they're doing.
I think they're doing
amazing technical work.
I think it's great.
I just, you know, essentially think they're,
they're wasting their time because,
and what his whole thesis seems to really
boil down to is at some point in the
future, Spotify is going to create this
algorithmic magic where mediocre or lower
tier podcasts can be found and
then get listens and then make,
and then Spotify will pay, pay them.
Yeah.
The YouTube model.
But that's, and I won't repeat
what, you know, Todd said,
because I think Todd comparing that
to YouTube showed that that's not,
that that's not feasible,
that YouTube doesn't pay.
Yeah.
What did he say?
0.25% or something?
Yeah.
But, but when you think about what he's
at, what he's asking for is the same,
same thing that people have been asking
for for a long time is he wants or thinks
somehow this, that there's going,
that Spotify is going to create
a creator economy middle class.
And they're not going to do that.
Yes.
Good point.
There's never been a creator economy
middle class and there never will be.
And it sucks.
It was just like blogging.
Remember blogging?
And what, you know, Andrew
was named Andrew Sullivan.
You know, he was taking, he was taking
subscriptions for his blog and,
you know, that he famously made a million
dollars and everyone's, I'm blogging.
I'm blogging.
Where's my money?
And that's how we got all
these crap display ads
everywhere that kind of kicked that off.
But there was something a little,
it's, and there's another piece to it.
And the, and, and as you, and it
ties into the creator middle class,
and you know how much I
don't like the word creator.
Um, I wrote that down just to
make it just to piss me off.
Yeah.
Worst work.
So the idea that you can just record a
podcast and then you upload it to some system
with magical algorithms
and it does all the rest.
The monetization, the, uh,
the marketing, et cetera.
That's the farce.
Look at Spotify's core
business, music business.
How did most of those people get there
by selling your own merch at your gigs,
by booking your own gigs,
by accepting to have the stupid drummer
in the band because his dad owns the van.
I mean, all of this stuff, printing
up your t-shirts, doing your mailers,
you know, sleeping at girlfriends' houses
who would then go out and spread flyers.
I'm, I'm, I'm describing
the hair band lifestyle,
but it's very similar for music and you
push and you push and you push and you make
no money and you, and you're starving.
And then if you're lucky, I
know many who have, you know,
grassroots gone up and then could have
their pick of the letter with some kind of
monetization event in
the form of a contract.
But even a lot of the smart ones,
look at where they wound up,
not owning their stuff, not
getting the right money.
They have to fight the public, the
performance rights organizations.
And then large corporations, big
technology, lobbies the U.S. Congress.
They come up with statutory
rates for what your
product is worth on a per stream basis.
If that's the future, then buh-bye.
You'll have a very limited, you won't
have 600,000, you'll have 60,000.
Maybe, maybe.
So it just, it doesn't make, this is
not, I don't think it ever will be a,
just go ahead, walk in, it all
works perfect, and, and, and,
and you're making money.
It's a, that's a pipe dream.
Well, listen to Daniel.
Daniel Eck said this a few months ago,
and he got a bunch of flack for it.
The CEO of Spotify, he said,
There's a narrative fallacy here,
combined with the fact that obviously some
artists that used to do well in the past
may not do well in this future landscape,
where you can't record
music once every three to
four years and think
that's going to be enough.
The artists today that are making it realize
that it's about creating a continuous
engagement with their fans.
It is about putting the work in, about
the storytelling around the album,
and about keeping a continuous
dialogue with your fans.
He concluded, I feel really that
the ones that the, this, uh.
You're breaking up, Jim.
I fuzzed out.
Yeah.
He said, I concluded.
Take another hit.
Quick, take another hit.
It'll be, it gets better.
I feel really that the real,
the ones that aren't doing well in streaming
are predominantly people who want to
release music the way
it used to be released.
I mean, that is the CEO of
Spotify basically saying,
if you want to be successful
in the creator economy,
you've got to work your butt off.
That's the way that it works now.
There is no algorithm,
there's, and you know,
the reason there's no
algorithm that will do it for
you is because it's not
an algorithm issue.
This is not an, whether
or not you have listeners
is not a function of an
algorithm or discovery.
What, what harms small podcasters in gaining
listeners is not the algo, it's time.
I rarely ever add a new podcast to my
lineup because I'm, I'm maxed out already.
I have a few podcasts
that I listen to for,
for work and have a few podcasts
I listen to for pleasure.
And that combined is small is so many hours
of listening per week that I can't even
listen to them all as
it, as it stands now.
So that means if I ever have, if I ever
add anything to my existing lineup, um,
it has to be truly mind
blowing, amazing content.
And the difference between
good and amazing is huge.
It's not a matter of media, of sort of,
I say mediocre and I
don't mean it derogatory.
What I'm saying is content
that is not extremely good.
To you.
To, to me, yes, to, to me,
um, that content, it does,
it can't get into most people's lineups
because most people already have a lineup
that is pretty solid.
And an algorithm that exploit, that
just boosts random stuff to the top,
isn't going to change that.
I mean, it's not an, it's just
not an algorithm issue to solve.
No, it's, it, it's trying to shoehorn
podcasting into something that it isn't.
And it just doesn't work that way.
You're right.
Even from the basic, at the
basic consumption level,
it's a very different experience.
Um, uh, people tend to be very
sticky if they get there, if,
if they get to that point,
but it's not like a subscribe to the,
to my YouTube channel and the algo will
pop it up for you once in a while.
It's just, it's a whole different beast.
Yeah.
And I'm sorry, go ahead.
Well, I was just going to say that RSS
is 99% of what is already in Spotify.
It's not like they're a silo.
They're not Spotify.
Their whole catalog is RSS feeds.
They haven't turned off the spigot yet.
And so when you're talking about
quote unquote, being on Spotify,
99% of the podcasts that are on Spotify
came there from third party hosting,
whether that's, whether that's, uh,
anchor or all, or all the other hosts.
So RSS is the crux of
what Spotify is doing.
So I still, again, I still don't understand
what, what the real core issue is here.
It seems like a, like a, a
misunderstanding or a misstatement of, of,
of who the two parties are, because if
you want, if you wanted to have your,
your show on Spotify exclusively
right now, you can't do that.
You're, if, even if you
create it on anchor,
you're still getting an RSS feed and
somebody like us will probably pick it up.
You will end up being on
multiple apps just by default.
So your best bet, if you want to use all
the, all this mythical, like Spotify,
uh, goodness, you, why not go create your,
your podcast on fireside and then let
it replicate to Spotify and just take
advantage of it all.
That way you're on Spotify, you get
their magic, whatever that magic may be,
and you get to be in every other,
every other directory and app also.
Yeah, but it's, to me,
this is a Slack channel conversation and I
think it's been going on for a long time
and I don't know if anyone really cares.
I do want to dispel one
rumor, um, you know,
no agenda is used as a value for
value example and we pioneered it.
I think, um, when, when
someone says, yeah,
but Adam Curry is a cult of
personality somehow meaning that, oh,
of course I'm famous.
Uh, uh, we, what started as a 20 minute
Skype call, uh, has now lasted 14 years.
We grew very slowly, maybe 15% year
over year, um, had to sell, uh,
possessions to feed myself during it.
Um, and it, it, it was, you know, at the
time, even today, cult of personality.
Now it started off as washed up VJ
and some old tech dude, you know,
this was not, not the kind of
marketing you're looking for.
So it, it, it, it's just what it takes.
And those early shows from when y'all
first started, they weren't, they, I mean,
the sound quality was poor.
I mean, they were not,
they were not anything like
what people understand
the no agenda show to be like today.
No, but that grew and, and, and that's,
and that's exactly my point is it grew.
We started to understand and that
may be for just a few people.
It's very possible that
not everybody can do that.
Well, you may be able to sing,
but it doesn't mean you belong
on Spotify with getting money.
Well, you think about the biggest cult
of personality that there are, uh,
that there is the Obamas.
I mean, that they would classify
as a cult of personality
to pretty much anybody with a brain.
And they, uh, they spun off.
They're not exclusive
with Spotify anymore.
There are RSS feeds now.
They left the silo.
We can only guess why.
Yeah.
I mean, like there's your
example of a, of a podcast.
I mean, that's never talked about anymore.
Uh, another cult of personality.
I mean, these are political people,
but you know, Bill Clinton,
he's got a podcast with
the Clinton Foundation.
So does Hillary.
None of these ever show
up in the top spots.
So what, I mean, just because you have a
name or a cult of personality at some point
in your, in your life, doesn't mean
that you instantly get audience.
That's absolutely true.
It's not given to you.
You have to pay, you have to,
you have to pay the dues just like
everybody else does and earn that audience.
One other thing I learned that
Spotify de-platform shows weekly.
Oh, I didn't.
Yeah, that was surprising.
I didn't know that.
That was surprising to me.
Uh-huh.
I'm not sure what that's about.
Well, anyway, the news this morning,
I think, puts everybody on notice.
I think it's much bigger
news than people realize.
And this is the acquisition of Pocket Cast,
uh, by, uh, automatic, by WordPress.com.
Give me your, uh, initial
impression of that.
Uh, I know, Matt.
Uh, we were both in San Francisco.
In fact, we lived in the same
building in San Francisco when, uh,
I was doing Pod Show.
He was just starting, I think he had
just, he had some transaction event.
I don't know if he raised
money or what, what it was.
And, um, he's very, very
sweet, soft talking man.
And, uh, we've exchanged emails over
the, over the course of the years.
Maybe just a hit, check it out, whatever.
I don't, you know, but not, not an intent.
I haven't, I definitely have not communicated
with him for, oh, at least a decade.
Um, of course I sent him
an email this morning
congratulating him
because the way I see it,
they have a, uh, as far as I know, a
very good business with WordPress.com.
Um, now they also, they
purchased something else.
Uh, what else did they purchase?
Uh, something that was not working well.
Oh, uh, Tumblr.
Tumblr, right, right, right, Tumblr.
So, you know, Tumblr is great for them
because that's an RSS-based acquisition,
the way I see it.
Tumblr always had RSS feeds.
I don't know if they still do.
I think so.
Um, and they had kind of a published
subscribe mechanism, as far as I know,
based on RSS, or at least
architected around RSS.
So, WordPress is, uh, has
a lot of things in one.
And depending on what you're doing,
it has, you know, server hosting,
it has a publishing
platform, it has a content management
system, uh, there's plugins.
In fact, there's an excellent plugin
for podcasting 2.0 that you can add.
And bringing that full circle, having
a podcast app, a successful, well,
successful in that
people use it financially, uh, it's
been a disaster for the investors.
They've lost a lot of money.
I think NPR owned a piece of them
or all of them at some point.
So that's, you know, clearly
this is a fire sale.
Um, but what an opportunity
to bring a complete different
experience than any other
quote unquote major app.
Pocket Cast, I would say,
is, is very popular.
It's up there.
Would you say it's overcast level?
Oh yeah.
Definitely.
Yeah.
It's, it's, it's a major,
it is a major app.
Yes.
A hundred percent.
Um, so it would make sense to differentiate
by having a hosting platform.
And with that, I don't mean
necessarily where your file is,
but a hosting platform that delivers
new features to an app that you either
brand or co-brand, what you at least,
you know, is integrated.
And, um, if he's not thinking
podcasting 2.0 with the namespace,
I'm going to have to go
out to San Francisco and
stand in front of his door.
It's a logical move.
I mean, that's the differentiator
right there and holy crap, that would,
I think that would stir
some, stir some stuff up.
Oh yeah, I do.
I think that was probably
the greatest, uh,
outcome for that app
that anybody could have
hoped for within the open RSS
community is there's some, you have,
now you have an owner
instead of the app dying, which
would have been terrible.
You know, everybody hates that
to have a, um, cause a lot of,
there's a lot of pocket cast
users who are just really dedicated to that
app, just like there are with, you know,
overcast users and, and each individual
app has their own sort of following.
Um, pod friend has a, is developing a big
following and there's a lot of people that
are just really like that app.
Um, and then, uh, pod verse too.
There's obviously a lot of pod verse
follow, uh, people come, you know,
being really committed
to that app phone, phone
boy loves that app.
Um, so whenever you have an
app with a following, I mean,
for it to die is just terrible.
Nobody, nobody wants that to happen.
And the one thing with
pocket cast that I saw
that never made any sense was
how much money they spend.
I mean, oh my God, what
were they spending it on?
Oh gosh, it was millions.
I think I mean, like they, uh,
whatever their loss was like
their annual loss or quarterly
loss was like a, a
staggering amount of money.
And I was like, wow, how in the world
are they spending this much money?
And so I don't know, you know, of course,
nobody knows what's going to
happen in an acquisition,
but if automatic can take that, uh,
and trim whatever needs to
be trimmed in order to make
their budget sane and, and
sustainable, and then on top of that,
commit that app to the
open RSS ecosystem and on all of its
features, uh, new features moving forward.
I mean, that's a, that's a
great outcome for everybody.
I think it's huge.
And I think a lot of people
should, should pay attention.
And, and actually this comes, um,
right on the heels of an interesting
conversation I had, uh, this week.
Yeah.
So, um, I can talk about this.
I'm not going to tell you who he is because
we didn't discuss me disclosing it,
but it's, it's not that
hard to figure out.
And the whole point is I want to
put people in touch with him is a,
a venture capital firm
that has pretty much exclusively,
they created a fund exclusively
for lightning, uh, projects.
And so they have, uh, investments in, um,
a lot of the wallets, you know, voltage,
a breeze, you know, they, they
invest in the future of lightning.
And I spoke to one of the three partners
and he sought me out and I was just,
we were just chatting and it kind of dawned
on, it was kind of, I love, by the way,
this is my favorite kind of, uh,
meeting where a, a venture person says,
it doesn't sound like you need any money.
I said, no, no, we're not, we're
not looking for any either.
He said, well, okay, well, how
can I, how can I, what can I do?
He actually had three questions.
I don't have them here, but he
said, what would move the needle?
What would really make a difference?
And then I said, well,
um, you know, there's,
there's a lot of app
development that may or
may not, you know, I'm
sure there's people who
would love to take investment for that,
but maybe no one wants to say, but
really where the biggest problem lies.
And he's, I think he's
an old infrastructure
guy at heart from the cloud stores days.
He said, um, so there's all, you
know, why is not everything adopted?
So, well, it's, you know,
it's a big deal to make changes within
a hosting company to the workflow.
You know, if it's really a
tricky, if you mess one thing up,
you could have a hundred thousand
customers whose feeds break, you know,
even just slightly as a huge issue.
I said, really what the
hosting companies do
is they spend a lot of time on education.
And that's why I believe there's
loyalty to those companies.
And he said, well, um, he says, I
do, you know, seed investments.
Can you find for me, uh, uh,
a host that, uh, you know,
that 50 or a hundred thousand dollars
would make a difference for, uh,
to then become completely podcasting
2.0 compliant, including value block.
And I said, yeah, I said, I don't know
exactly there's, there's gotta be 25,
at least hosting companies.
And I have no idea.
We don't know even, but
a fraction of them.
Um, but if, uh, if you have a hosting
company and you're interested, uh,
email me adam at curry.com and
I'll put you in touch with them.
I just thought that was like, wow,
you know, that I think that would be,
it would be great
for me to be able to say, you know, here,
here's all the podcast companies that,
uh, that have 2.0 features,
here's one that has them all.
That, that would help.
So, you know, that's, that's the big
pushback from hosting companies is,
I mean, like we're going to do this
stuff, but really there's that, you know,
the whole waiting for adoption,
uh, angle, which is always an issue.
But then also like, I mean,
how can we justify spending this
much dev time in order for it,
for it to, to put in a feature
that we're just not sure that,
that we're going to get any traction on.
Right.
And so, but if somebody shows up
and says, oh, here's 50 grand,
here's a hundred grand
that changes the, that
changes the dynamic.
And then all of a sudden you
can, you can justify the time.
Well, it's interesting because I said,
you know, we have a couple, uh, uh,
a couple of companies we work with who are
very, very proactive, very progressive.
They've, they've really integrated a lot.
Very, very proud of that.
Um, he says, oh, I know
this is exactly, he says,
I was going around for years selling
cloud hosting and, uh, he would
typically hear, well, you know,
this is 10 year infrastructure.
It ain't broke.
We don't really want to fix it.
You know, all the, all the things that
we've heard different versions of,
not from all, but different versions
of, he said, but then when it took off,
it commoditized almost overnight.
People didn't even know
it, how fast that went.
And, and when that happened,
a lot of players went away.
Yeah.
I can see that.
That that's, that's the other
thing is it's not just about, uh,
being forward looking.
It's about being able to spot the one
thing that you need to possibly pivot to.
I mean, and that's harder.
That's a harder thing to do.
Cause you get, you know,
there, okay, well,
our business has been
going for 15 years and
we're still cruising.
Sure.
Uh, we don't, you know, well,
I mean, you know, this is,
we don't have to think about this
or, uh, we're just going to sit back.
I mean, and that, that really
can bite you overnight.
I don't know who, you know,
nobody knows the future, but no,
I mean, that's cool, man.
I, that would be, that would be amazing to
have a host pop up and do that to be sort
of full stack podcasting 2.0.
Yeah.
I mean, that'd be incredible.
I mean, I'm sure he wants, uh, he
wants, he has a interesting portfolio.
So, you know, he could, there's all
kinds of companies that could help with,
you know, how far they want to go
with, with the lightning stuff,
but at least get the value block in.
You know, I've been working with
a guy in the Bitcoin world too.
He's, he's super jazzed about this,
uh, about the whole, you know,
lightning ecosystem stuff.
And so we, um, you know,
I've been just chatting with him on
Telegram and he has been talking
about, you know, he's, he says,
this is magical being able to
pay people right in the app as
you listen and as you enjoy their content,
you're responding with, with value.
And he just, he, he
said, it's just amazing.
He loves it.
And so, I mean, there are
real people with real
money and influence who
are out there looking
to further this, that specific technology
because it meets their ideals, uh,
it meets their business
goals, uh, and all kinds
of various things.
So it may look to some of
the podcasting world and
the podcasting world doesn't really
understand Bitcoin very well.
And they look to the
podcasting world that the
crypto side of the podcasting 2.0 stuff
is just sort of, uh, aspirational
hobbyist type thing.
But I think it's a little more
concrete than people understand.
It's a huge company.
Well, huge.
There's a well-funded company behind
the lightning network, not behind it,
but behind the protocol.
There's, um, gosh, I forgot
how much money was in the,
I saw the number the other day.
It's like a thousand Bitcoin or something.
It's got to be $300 million that we
know of that's, uh, in node liquidity.
Hold on a second, Dave.
38 minutes.
Here's your cue to boost.
Come on.
You know you want to.
Who else gives you?
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Whoa, whoa.
What?
Well, I've got, um, I've
brought cane bearing gifts.
Uh-oh.
Um, ISO boost.
Boost.
Nice.
Hold on.
It's going right into the rack.
Ah, excellent.
Boost.
We got this one, of course.
We still have the, uh, the Fauci.
Boost.
That is, uh, that is our
buddy, Kyle Hebert, the, the,
the voice actor and host of
the Intergalactic Boombox.
Ah, I thought I recognized that undertone.
Yeah.
Nah, that guy's a badass.
He's awesome.
He sent me a bunch of stuff.
I got a, I'm going to
trickle him out to you.
All right.
I'm now, now in the rack,
it gets the orange color.
He's got the color code.
Yeah.
All the boosts have orange color.
Of course.
Are you crazy?
Oh, nice.
Yeah.
Um, yeah.
I didn't mean to interrupt
you with that, but.
No, that's not.
Um, I think that, so for me, this
has been a great week with, um,
there's money out there
for a small hosting company.
It would have to be small.
I, I'm, I'm sure, you know, uh, the guys,
we know that the a
hundred thousand dollars
for a piece of their companies
beyond any reality, you know,
they're much more valuable
than that for a seed round, but
there may be someone out there.
Um, and then the, the WordPress
pocket cast, boom, I mean, what a,
what an opportunity and
can't see any reason, you
know, even leave the,
even if you leave the value block out of
it, what an opportunity to
differentiate and with a, with a,
a large audience and really
show what can be done.
Uh, do you want to talk
about some namespace stuff?
Cause we, yeah.
Yeah.
I can guess I got a bunch
of stuff to talk about.
Uh, let's see.
I mean, we're gearing up.
We're sort of got to think
about phase four now.
Wait, you know what?
Before we do that, just one other topic.
Um, since I did the boost
and I called the time,
you have made something so obvious and
so beautiful and I see this morning that
I've already received a number of PMs.
This is the payment message.
And, uh, I mean, I'm
seeing stuff coming in.
I mean, this is someone poost, poosted,
someone, someone, someone that, uh,
they posted, they posted, there it is.
That's our word.
You got a boost.
You got a poost.
Uh, who is this?
Hello, gentlemen.
You have, you have the
pleasure of getting the
first boost message ever from pod friend.
Well, technically this is the third,
but only because I didn't grab
a screenshot of the first two.
So that's from Martin.
Oh, did this just come in?
It just came in.
Yeah.
Martin's testing.
Exactly.
There it is.
I love you podcasting 2.0 and,
um, and has a timestamp there,
although only for nerds.
So this would be one hour and 10 minutes.
Okay.
But nerds would say 80 minutes.
Oh, I can't tell.
I can't get the stats.
The stats are blank.
Oh yeah.
Um, wow.
Okay.
So that means, okay, that Martin, see,
we should be doing this show live.
We should be giving live,
uh, tutorial feedback.
Well, I, I, I have a feeling that
is within our imminent future.
I think so too.
It seems like people are
developing that way.
So yeah.
And that may be a perfect, anyway.
No.
So just, just tell us what
you've done because this is,
this is quite magical where you're
just sitting alone at home.
An email comes in.
It says you have a payment message.
You've got a boost.
And, uh.
No, no, no, no.
The boost is not going to,
that needs to be eradicated.
And it gives you the timestamp.
It should give us the number of Satoshis.
Um, it has a, I guess a, uh, a user alias,
uh, the app name and, uh, a message.
And that, and that alerts you
on email when it comes in.
Now that there's something
triple, triple joy to that.
One, I just, someone is,
is listening to my product at
this very moment and liked it so
much they sent something.
Um.
That's a crazy feeling.
I'm responding to Martin on the, on
the Mastodon that we got his message.
Oh, cool.
Uh, yeah, we got it.
Okay.
So, what, if anybody has no
idea what we're talking about.
Yes.
That's what I was going for.
The payment message is, uh,
you can see it right now in CurioCaster
and Martin's baking it in as well.
So, you go to CurioCaster, uh,
go to the podcast that you want
to send payment to, and let's
say you want to make a donation.
Okay.
So, you're, you're listening to,
you, you've got a favorite podcast.
You want to go and just
give them some money
just like you would with PayPal or buy me
a coffee or Patreon or blah, blah, blah.
You go and you find that
podcast on CurioCaster.
Uh, you got your wallet set up
there with your sats in it.
Then you can hit the payment message button
and it comes up and you can say, okay,
I want to give them this many
sats and I want, here's my name.
You can put in a nickname
or a moniker and then
here's a message and you can type up to
like 500 characters of a message.
It's just like a PayPal donation.
Yeah.
You put that in there.
Only, only you don't have to log
in, doesn't open your browser.
It's right there in the app.
Click message, boom, done.
And it comes in as an email.
I love it.
It's so simple, but yet, oh my God.
On the tech side.
So what's happening is
that message comes into
our node with the appropriate that, excuse
me, that payment comes in and it's
got a TLV payload, which is like a,
the TLV is a, uh,
what was it?
Time length.
Variable.
Value.
I can't remember what the, yeah.
Something I, it's not, I forgot
what the, uh, acronym stands for,
but it's an encoded value.
It's a hex encoded value.
And so all that data comes in and
it's basically just a blob of Jason.
And then we, we, once every five minutes,
we pull the latest transactions
from our lightning
node and parse out all the TLV records.
And then if, if one of them has
the TLV, if one of them has the,
the message field and
the name field, uh, it would be send,
I think it's called sender name.
And then there's another one.
And this is the one
that Martin is missing.
Another field is a value MSAT total.
That means the value, the total
value in, in mill of Satoshis.
Right.
If those three fields are present,
uh, we get a message, uh,
over it converts it to an email
and sends it to us with the message,
the name of the sender, the app,
it came through and the
total sats donated.
And it's just like getting
a PayPal donation.
It is awesome.
Did you see, we got a, an actual
donation donation with a note?
Yeah, I got, yeah, I saw this one.
I've got it in the stack.
Okay, good.
All right.
I wasn't going to give it away because
when that came in, I was like, oh, okay.
Boom, boom.
What are we doing here?
This is crazy.
I know it's, it's nuts, man.
I'm so excited about this.
Let's just stand here.
We're just standing for a second, Dave.
Congratulations, man.
What a great job.
That's so cool.
But less than a year.
Look at this.
That, no, it's nuts.
I mean, and it's so cool to have, uh,
so many other app developers
that are sort of sharing
the vision and they're like,
oh yeah, this is great.
I'm going to go do it.
And it's like this instant
feedback mechanism.
It's so fun.
Yeah.
I love it.
Uh, so maybe that's a good jumping off
point to get into namespace since, uh,
this is namespace related.
Um, well, I mean, in general,
I mean, we just got to think,
I'm thinking about what's the
goal for phase four and the
natural one is comments.
Um, yeah, I know.
And by the way, uh, James Cridland,
there's no bun fight over.
What's a bun fight anyway?
It's something British guys do.
You don't want to know.
Yeah.
Okay.
Um, he said on pod land, no,
it's comment sounds great,
but it sounds like there's a, you know,
disagreement between the developers.
We're going to do chat or comments.
I think that was two weeks ago.
Yeah.
That's not the, that's, uh,
that's not really a fight.
That's just a, a recognition that we
were talking about two different things.
Um, and which we were,
which was fantastic because that we
didn't have to have a big meeting.
We didn't have, we didn't have
to have all hands, all hands.
We're confused.
It worked out.
It was nice.
I like that.
By the way, I like, uh, to hear Sam
Sethi call it a baseball match.
That's a, that's a pretty
fun, uh, British Britishism.
Well, that's because it's a baseball
game, not a baseball match.
It's because everybody
knows that cricket takes
four days and eight times you got to have
tea and no one wants to deal with it.
So we prefer nine innings done.
Um, I think the, I think the battle, if
there is one, uh, really boils down to,
I guess it would be two things,
whether to do it at all.
And I think, uh, and that's got reasons.
Uh, and then if we do it, how are we going
to do it in a way that is responsible?
Because there's, uh, those are
two sort of related topics.
Cause if you're doing comments, if you're
doing descent, decentralized comments,
and this is where Alex
got upset yesterday.
If you're doing decentralized comments,
you have to understand that
you are creating something
that has the potential to
launch things out into
the universe that you cannot take back.
So if I put out it, we're,
we're used to Twitter and YouTube
where you can post a comment and
then decide that you regret that
comment and delete it or edit it.
But in a decentralized system
like Mastodon, for instance,
we think that's happening, but
that doesn't necessarily have to happen.
So if I could create a Mastodon server
today, go in, edit the code and not,
and have my Mastodon
instance, not honor the removal of posts.
And therefore I would see everything
for all time and you can't delete it.
So there has to be a recognition
amongst everybody who works on this,
that that is a reality of, of, of the
situation when it comes to activity pub.
Now you, we, we, we can make some other
thing that potentially is able to,
to work around that,
but I'm not sure what the
appetite for creating
something from scratch to that level is.
So there, the only
solution, quote unquote,
there's really is no solution
to that specific problem.
But the only thing that we need to
make sure of is that if, if we do it,
we have to build in lots
of safeguards where, uh,
people fully understand that
that's the case when they do it.
Okay.
So that's interesting because I think that
conversation started with moderation,
the topic of moderation and
who moderates, et cetera.
And as far as I know, it evolved
to, okay, you can say, yes,
I want comments on my podcast or no.
And I think that's, I think that's,
um, that's something that if you,
you should be able to determine
that in your feed, uh, like a,
uh, a robots.txt file.
And otherwise, if you say yes,
then it is what it is and you get it problem
or the potential problem I see is spam,
not moderation, but spam.
Uh, I think that there are my, okay.
I think there's multiple problems.
Like, so it's not yes,
yes, spam and moderation.
There's also just mess ups.
So suppose that you, and I've,
I've done this, you, you're,
you think you're typing in one box and
you're typing in something else on the
screen, type something
else and you hit enter.
Yeah.
You see what I mean?
Like, yeah, you can accidentally
type something that
you completely do not
want the universe to see.
And the idea that you can't take
it back is kind of a big deal.
And that falls outside
of the moderation issue.
Yeah, it does.
It's like, oh crap.
Now what do I do?
Um, it's sort of like, it's like
sending a text message or an email.
Once it goes out, you can't get it back.
It's, it's there.
So people, and so what,
what will happen is wherever the
locus of control ends up being, if,
if we're talking about activity
pub and activity pub, the,
the sort of root node for,
for a podcast episode.
Yeah.
If it resides with a
podcaster on their system,
then in one of these mistakes are made
where somebody accidentally posts something
that they didn't mean to,
that podcaster has to understand they're
going to get blown up with that person
frantically trying to get
the, them to take that off.
Wasn't this the exact point that this
is where I think Alex got frustrated.
He says that just won't be possible.
That's not how it's going to work.
He actually said, no one listens to me.
I'm out.
I hope he's coming back.
He is.
Yeah, no, he is.
He's the, there is a, when it
comes to a topic, to a topic,
this sort of challenging, uh, there are
going to be constant misunderstandings.
Yeah, but we, we got the
group for it though, man.
I'm, I'm proud of this
group working through it.
Yeah.
I mean, you should have seen some of the
stuff that some of them flame, warm,
epic meltdowns that happened on
the EC2 for poets mailing list.
Oh my goodness.
This is so calm.
So civil.
Yeah.
I mean, this was an every other day occurrence
that somebody was calling somebody an
ugly word and saying, I'm out.
I mean, so I don't,
this doesn't bother me.
These flare ups don't bother me at all.
Well, you're, you're an IT guy.
You've dealt with this.
Yeah.
Well, it's, it's, it's almost necessary.
So there has to be a necessary
tension between, uh, I want one,
between one group that says, oh man, I really
want to create this really cool thing.
And another group that says, let's
not create a 10 headed monster.
Yeah.
There has to be that tension.
And for each, for each different thing
that we do, that group can switch sides.
Oh yeah.
And so this is good.
This is necessary to have this tension and
to have these sort of flare ups because
it lets you know that this is serious.
And I'll, I'll give you a perfect example.
I was gung ho, gung ho on payment messages
and just going, boom, boom, boom.
Let's do this.
And Cridlin jumped in and just made a
big deal about the harassment thing.
And he, at first I was annoyed by it and
I was like, oh, can you get over it?
But then, you know, the longer he
went on, I thought, you know what?
This is really important to him.
If it's that important, I
need to stop and listen.
And so, you know, we stopped,
we listened, we slowed down.
And I think we came up with a
better solution that's going to,
is going to protect most of his concerns.
So that, having these flare ups is good
because it really does sort of shock you,
you know, like slaps you awake
and says, okay, all right, wait,
let me slow down and make sure that I'm
not letting my passion override the,
what could possibly leave legitimate
concerns from other people.
I agree.
And I had this, I had a similar reaction.
My reaction was more of, oh, it would
have been nice if you said, great idea.
Here's a concern I have.
But that's British.
You know, the British, sometimes they,
Dutch do weird, have weird approaches too.
So I understand that.
I agree.
And I think we did come up
with an elegant solution.
I don't know if it's all fleshed out
yet, but I like the idea of a threshold,
which is kind of, it's interesting.
You know, when we first started
talking about comments,
we were looking at the Sphinx
tribe model, which is, you know,
completely not scalable for
what we're talking about.
But the idea that you pay, I mean,
it's basically what we're doing now is you
want to send a message to the podcaster,
you're paying for it.
And whether it's one Satoshi
or a thousand Satoshis,
the message payload will still
go and still come in unless,
and this is what I like, is a threshold.
So, well, you know, if you want
to send me a message, and this,
in a weird way, comes back to an old idea
that I think Bill Gates and a couple other
Silicon Valley guys had way back when,
when spam on email became a problem.
Oh, we have to have, you know,
a way, like a digital stamp.
Do you remember those days?
Oh, yeah.
Oh, my goodness.
And there was, and of course, it was
completely not doable, but here it is.
I mean, this, this closed loop
by itself is interesting.
And the idea that-
It wasn't doable then, but it did become,
the concept did, was pointed out,
and it became something
that was doable like DKIM.
Like what?
DKIM, like DKIM.
Like- Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Yes, exactly.
So, that's perfect.
And that's why I think the, the payment
message is a beautiful enhancement.
It's a super idea.
Um, and this, you know, this enormous
backend fun we can have with,
with that data and, um,
just fits so perfectly into the
value for value model in general.
But you're so right.
And so now we have, I think,
I don't think we've quite gotten
through all the comment stuff yet.
And I don't think we're quite ready for
namespace, but the leaders in the space,
and this is what I like,
is, of course, Castapod.
I'm not even going to ask anymore.
Castapod and Martin doing, as far as
I know, the first app implementation.
It's very exciting.
When that, when that stuff happens,
it's like, okay, stand back, magic,
sparks are going to fly.
Yeah.
Well, this is what I was kind of talking
about on the last show was that we,
there's a, there's a little bit of,
we have to have somebody do
an implementation first.
I feel like, um, Alex has also said that
he's going to write a blog post about it,
detailing sort of where he's coming from.
He also has a lot of
experience in this, of course.
I didn't want to leave him out.
Yeah.
And so I think that will be really good.
I'm, I'm, I'm waiting sort
of on that and to see what,
what happens with this, because I don't
even know really what to document yet.
Right.
I watched the dev meeting
and I understand it.
And I did some, some more digging on,
on activity pub this week and played around
with a little bit of code and it all
makes a lot of sense.
It's just, we are going to have to see
an implementation first and then, um,
and then, and then listen a lot and,
and see what, what needs to happen.
There, there's other stuff
we can do in the meantime.
That's not, uh, another,
another Alex, um, proposal.
And this is one he's been batting
around for a while in various forms.
And I think I finally understand it
now is, uh, the podcast medium tag.
Ah, this is so we can understand
if it's a video, if it's a song,
if it's a podcast, if
it's a PDF or whatever.
Yeah.
Uh, so I'll, I'll just sort of read a
little bit of what his proposal was.
Uh, he says this helps solve the is about
problem where a category on its own is
otherwise too ambiguous.
And he says, this tag tells the application
what the content contained within the
feed is, as opposed to what the content
is about in the case of a category.
Um, and then he says, uh,
if this tag is not defined,
the medium should default to podcast.
So that's the default.
Uh, and so I think that last
little bit than where he says,
if the tags are not defined, the
medium should default to podcast.
To me, that's when the, when
the light bulb went on,
I think I finally understand what
he means because what he's not,
he's not defining different
types of podcasts.
He's defining different types
of meat of content that,
that can be delivered in the XML
podcast, quote unquote podcast way,
but they're not a podcast.
Like in the sense, in the sense
of what we all think one is.
And so he gives a few examples.
Uh, let's see.
So obviously this fault is podcast.
Uh, another example of a,
of a medium would be music.
And he describes that as a feed of music
organized into an album with each,
with each item, a song within the album.
Abel Kirby is hitting the boost
button real hard right now.
He better be.
I helped him set up his feed.
Um, he says, uh, music has existed as a
medium for a very long time and dedicated
music applications already exist.
So this is a good
justification, uh, video.
And he describes that as like a podcast,
but used in a more visual experience.
Uh, another one is film.
And he says that specific types
of video with one item per feed.
And then he also gives audio book, specific
types of audio with one item per feed.
Yes, of course.
Audio book.
Yep.
I think this makes a lot of sense.
And I would like to do this in
phase four, uh, because let's,
it lets the app know in advance what they're
getting themselves into when they begin
to render the content of this podcast.
Well, exactly.
And, uh, if it's a, uh, if it's
a film or, oh, documentary,
which this may actually
be needed to move the
breeze web LN documentary project forward.
Uh, cause that's stuck.
Maybe, maybe Roy stopped loving me.
That's also possible.
Well, uh, did you, uh, the new beta of
breeze said it has some LN URL stuff.
No, uh, no LN URL is
different from web LN.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I get confused every time.
Yeah.
And they're going to do it.
I know that they've been doing the LN URL,
but the reason why the reason I bring
it up is you might want to present that
differently on the screen.
Letterboxd, you know, full screen.
There's a whole bunch of
different things that
you could assume or that would make sense.
Uh, maybe even a different skin, you know,
an audio book may have to be presented
differently than a podcast with,
with different features
in different places,
or maybe the chapter
list on the side open.
I mean, I, a notes list, you know, a
notepad for taking notes, annotations,
a lot of different things.
It could be anything.
And if you know what it is in advance,
then the, the podcast player,
the app can transmorgify
into something, into a,
into an experience that is more
appropriate for audio books.
Yeah, totally.
Totally.
Yeah.
The audio or, um, a feature film,
you know, something like that.
I mean, those all have different needs,
uh, even to the point where how you, um,
how you display the transcripts.
You do want, you do exactly, exactly.
You want to put them on, you know,
like on a show notes style, uh,
what do you call it?
Like a, like a tab, or do you want to
overlay it as subtitles on the film,
on the film?
So you, you have all these
different considerations.
I think having something that gives
the app a hint, uh, it's a great idea.
It's a good idea.
Do you want to do some more namespace
stuff before we thank some people?
Um, I don't know.
It's up to you.
You, you can call the shots.
Boost!
Does that mean, does that
mean we're thanking people?
We're thanking people right now.
This is a value for value
project, the whole thing.
All right.
Uh, the podcast, uh, the servers,
the Mastodon, uh, everything.
Everything that goes on
here is a value for value.
Uh, we're very, very proud
to have supporters who, uh,
even have subscriptions consistent.
It's incredibly kind.
Everybody is supporting the show.
A number of ways to do it.
You can go to podcastindex.org,
go down to the bottom and click
on the big red donate button
to send some cuck bucks our way.
Now, um, whatever you send,
make it meaningful to you.
I love people sending a number that,
that they're passionate about
or that they think is, uh,
the superstitious about.
Um, but it's, it's just as good for
someone to say, here's $5 I saved.
That is equally as meaningful
as any other amount.
And, and then that's
really the beauty of it.
You send back the value that you
receive from the entire project.
Now we also have, um, a number of
ways to, uh, contribute with, uh,
the lightning network.
And maybe we go straight to our first
lightning, uh, payment message donation.
Okay.
Because that was just exciting when
I saw that come in this morning.
Oh, okay.
I, we hadn't even asked for
it yet, but here it is.
Uh, came in through CurioCaster.
It's, uh, Stephen Bell.
He gave us a 20,000 sats, uh, $6.36.
And he says, thank you for your courage.
And thank you for your coding.
Can you please defrag me?
Of course.
Do we defragment on, on demand?
You know what was cool about that?
It was seeing the 20,000 Satoshis.
It's interesting.
You just translated that for me.
It didn't even matter.
I was like, 20,000 Satoshis.
That's, you know, that's a lot more than
a podcast normally gets for a boost.
I'm not even translating it anymore.
I'm, I'm in, I'm in sats world, baby.
It's like, uh, you, it's
like, it's like Dutch.
You just, it goes right to the brainstem.
You know, there's something to that.
There's something to that.
Thank you, Mr.
Uh, thank you, Stephen.
We've got a first ever official.
First page.
Yeah.
First poop.
Pust.
No, no, stop.
Okay.
So, uh, sorry.
I don't know how to pronounce this name.
T H I E R R Y.
Terry.
Is it just Terry?
It's from France.
Okay.
I looked, I did a, uh,
Google image search and I just
put that word Terry in there and
it was men and women both came back.
So this had helped me not at all.
So I have no idea if it's a man or woman.
That's true.
Uh, but whoever they
are, they gave us $100.
Wow.
And no note.
Well, we need a note because
you get a t-shirt for that.
I know.
So, uh, Terry, uh, Terry Bregant.
If you are out there, um, let us know.
Yeah.
Those t-shirts are quite good.
I must say quality wise.
They are.
They wash well.
They keep their color.
Uh, I like it.
It's, it's not bad.
I'm not cutting the grass in mine.
I'm keeping it in.
Oh yeah.
No, I, no, I only take this
out to fancy restaurants.
That's right.
Reservation only.
Uh, Martin Keefe gave us $50.
No note again.
Oh, all are.
Yeah.
Thank you, Martin.
Nice.
Uh, don't know where Martin's from.
Let's see.
Uh, Dreb Scott.
$46.
Episode number donation.
Ah.
He says, go podcasting.
Yeah.
Excellent.
Wait, I had a fail on that one.
Go podcasting!
Yeah.
Did you see the Sharknado
album art that he did?
After we were talking about, uh,
it wasn't, it was Shorsnado.
Yeah, Shorsnado.
Yeah, and it was fantastic.
And he's like, I'm not, I'm
not much of a, of an artist.
Well, it works.
It was beautiful.
Works for me.
Very, very punk rock.
Yeah, Dreb Scott does, uh, the
chapters and, uh, chapter,
cloud chapters and chapter art
for every podcast I'm doing.
And this one is no exception.
I know he probably rolls his
eyes every time I say this,
but I swear one day he is going
to run a podcast chapter creation
service and make lots of money.
Yeah, I think you're right.
You've mentioned this and he's,
he's got the process down.
He could, he could farm it out to people,
pay them in Satoshis for a
number of chapters they made.
Yeah.
You're so right.
And holy crap.
I mean, we already have him
in the value block split.
Mm-hmm.
He gets, what, five, five
percent of, uh, of everything.
Well, I asked him out of
curiosity this morning.
I was like, so how many sats do you have?
Or how many, how much
sats are you getting?
And, uh, he said, uh, he checked his, uh,
node and he said currently
he hasn't put it,
he hasn't taken sats out
for about two weeks and
he's got around 90,000 sats in his node.
So that's about 30 bucks
for over two weeks.
For over two weeks.
Wow.
If I'm understanding right,
that's the, you know,
and he can correct me if I'm wrong,
but I mean, that's, that's
really not bad at all.
Yeah.
And considering that, you
know, what he does is, I mean,
the worst part of the job is you
have to listen to the shows.
It is the worst part.
But using hypercatcher, it's super easy
because you're listening to the show.
He's a click.
Okay.
I'm going to chapter here to a
chapter here to chapter here.
You go back in the hypercatcher studio,
by the way, where's David Norman?
Uh, David Norman hates us
because he had a baby.
Oh, never, never compete against babies.
It's, it's, it's a bad,
bad business decision.
Martin Morrison, do not have children.
We need you.
That guy seems like he's primed, man.
You see, he's like, he, he just doesn't look
like the Nordic guy who's going to have
15 children looking just like him.
The Martin Van Trapp family.
Martin, Martin Jr.
Martin Jr.
Number two, number three, number four.
Even the girls are named Martin.
Everybody's a Martin.
Yeah.
Uh, Anthony Tomaszewski, and sure
got that wrong, uh, gave us $20.
Thank you very much.
By the way, uh, for the t-shirt,
you know, just keep track of your,
uh, of your donations.
And, uh, when you've, uh, when
you've reached a hundred dollars,
let us know if you're interested.
We'll be happy to send you one
of our, our fancy t-shirts.
Um, Mike Dell.
Everybody knows Mike.
Yeah.
Uh, Mike sent us a $10.73.
I'm not sure if that's
a numerology or not.
73 could be a ham radio, uh, 73s.
Kilo five, alpha, Charlie, Charlie.
Uh, uh, KC4NXA.
Yes.
That's a good call.
KC4NXA.
I like that.
He's an old, I'm an old one.
Uh, but he says, uh, I'm a ham to K8LMJ.
See?
And he says, I did the first
ham radio class of iPodcasting.
The ham radio pod class
is what he called it.
Excellent.
Yeah.
Thank you, Mike.
Yeah, Mike.
He, uh, he sent me a message the other
day and said, uh, said, hey, if, uh,
if you want
to get, you know, recertify, uh, we can get
a few guys together and, uh, and certify
you at podcast and podcast
movement in Nashville.
There you go.
Oh, well, yeah, you could
read the questions on the,
on the plane ride down and be fine.
Yeah.
I'll have where we're driving.
So I'll have Melissa drive and
I'll read the book on the way.
You should, you should
go straight for general.
Really?
I regretted not doing general because I
did the ham radio license real briefly.
You basically get a license to learn.
Um, uh, the test is available online.
The current test with the current answers,
but on the test you get
the three multiple choice
answers will be out of order
on the, uh, so it's really.
It's really not that difficult.
Even if you just have a very basic
understanding of the operation of ham radio,
um, for the general, there's, you
know, it's, it's a longer test.
There's more questions,
but the same adheres.
It's, you know, you can, you can take
the tests and there's the questions in,
in a, in a jumbled up order.
And I remember taking the technicians,
the guy said, he has so much time left.
You want to take the general.
And I said, I hadn't studied for it.
And I missed it by two, I think.
And then I had to wait a month before the
next, uh, the next licensing session.
And then I aced that one as well.
You know, the thing that always messes
me up is where you convert, uh,
meters to megahertz.
So you have the, so the, uh,
the, the, the, the, the,
the two meter band being 144 megahertz,
the 144, 145 megahertz.
Uh, yeah, that's for some reason,
the met the measurement of
distance rather than cycle
count always messes me up.
Right.
I think it's, you divide it by what?
300,000 million and then times the apex
of the moon and the speed of light.
Yeah.
Something like that.
I just know instinctively 20 meters,
14, 14 kilohertz, uh, you know,
above the 14, uh, John, John Chidgy
posted something the other day, uh,
about social distancing and it was
like, uh, engineer social distancing.
I don't know if you saw that.
It was like, instead of six feet
apart, it's like 150 megahertz about,
about three or something let's see here.
We got Brittany, Brittany
Tanksley gave us $10.
Thank you, Brittany.
Uh, no note.
There's an epidemic of no notes today.
Yeah.
Well, you know, they can just
choose to send it through, uh,
through a payment message and
the note is easy and it's easy to send
and, and PayPal doesn't take anything and.
And we get a chuckle
every time it happens.
We get a more than a chuckle.
It's like a little jolt of joy.
Uh, Jeffrey Rutherford, uh, took out a
$5 a month subscription with no notes.
Thank you very much, Jeffrey.
Thanks.
Subscription's always helpful.
Uh, and Jeremy Gerds also took
out a $5 a month subscription.
Thank you, Jeremy.
Thank you.
And, uh, we've got some monthly donors
that hit this week and let's see.
The rundown is David Norman, the phantom.
Oh, okay.
He, he, he, now this is a subscription,
so he could be actually
dead and it's just still
coming off his card.
So we've got maybe a year and
a half until his card expires.
We're good.
Okay.
Hey, Roland.
Thanks, David.
I hope the, I hope the baby's fine, man.
Send us pictures.
Come back.
Uh, Paul Saltzman.
You know, Paul, right?
Didn't you say you know Paul?
Paul forever.
Yeah.
At $22 and 22 cents.
Thank you, Paul.
Uh, Derek Visker, $21.
Damon, uh, Kasajak.
I'm, I, I'm sorry, Damon, I'm going to
butcher your name every month from ever.
Uh, $15.
Uh, Sorin Mueller, $10.
Jeremy Cavanaugh, $10.
Hey, well done on the Sorin.
Well done.
Oh, thank you.
An O with a, an O with a,
with a line through it.
Nice.
Um, I'm good at this stuff.
Chris Cowan, $5.
And Thomas Sullivan Jr., $5.
Excellent.
Well, we thank you all very much for
supporting Podcasting 2.0, the podcast.
But, you know, the board
meeting is just the
weekly summary where we report back to you
and let you know what's going on.
Um, and it feels like we
need, oh, again, thank you.
You can, uh, do a payment
message or you can, uh,
which is a Satoshi's lightning network,
or you can go to podcastindex.org
and hit the big red donate button.
Um, actually, we want to get back
in the namespace because we,
we kind of left it off last week
and I want to make sure we do enough.
Yeah.
Uh, play this first.
I got a couple of ones on, uh,
clips I want to play though.
These are just, uh, let's see, play first.
This one was from pragmatic and I
just want to, because it's sort of,
part of the donation segment.
And we've talked about value for
value and that kind of thing lately.
I want people to hear what, what
is, what a great idea it is.
How am I going to say this?
I would like to hear what
it sounds like when you
ask your audience to be
part of podcasting 2.0.
So play, uh, how it's done
pragmatic, John Chigi.
We're aging close to our monthly goal to
go advertising free across the network,
but we can only do that with your help.
Pragmatic is also a
podcasting 2.0 enhanced show.
Uh, and with the right podcast player,
you can also stream Satoshi's
as you listen at whatever
rate you prefer, giving
you complete control.
The choice is yours.
Just visit engineer.network.com
slash pragmatic to
learn how you can help this
show to continue to be made.
Nice.
That's value for value.
Excellent.
And I think all value for
value segments should be
done with Furelis playing
in the background.
Yeah, absolutely.
He was actually playing
that himself while talking.
That's hot.
No, I'm just kidding.
Um, how, uh, so then the other
one is how it's done, uh,
Matt O'Dell, Citadel, Dispatch.
I also want to thank all of the freaks
who constantly support this show,
uh, with their sats.
Um, I want to keep this show
completely audience supported, um,
with no ads and no sponsors.
I think it aligns incentives best.
Um, and I can't do that without your
support, so I do appreciate that.
The easiest way you can support
the show is via podcasting 2.0.
Um, you can look up different
podcast apps that support that.
That's newpodcastapps.com.
You can stream sats directly to
the show as you're listening.
It's pretty cool.
As I, I see the day after I post it,
I just see sats start coming
into my wallet, just streaming
in as people are listening.
Uh, it's really fucking powerful.
Um, you can also support the show.
If you're watching the video
stream through the LNURL,
QR code on the bottom left hand
screen, bottom left of your screen,
um, or going to sitledispatch.com.
You can support via tippin.me, uh,
if you prefer lightning or you can
support with the Samurai Paynim.
I think we need to change our t-shirts.
What?
Do you want to put a QR code on it?
Well, no, I want to have podcasting 2.0.
It's pretty fucking powerful.
Quote, uh, quote Matt O'Dell.
Matt O'Dell.
Yeah.
Anyway, I just, I thought those
were good sort of examples.
Well, that's how you do it.
That's how to ask.
And thank you, Matt, for
mentioning newpodcastapps.com.
It took a long time for that to catch on.
Yeah.
You know, Kyle Hebert does
that too on every show.
I'm going to get a clip of that as well.
He's, I mean, he just, that's how you ask.
You got to ask.
I dropped it on a Rogan a couple
of times when I was there.
Oh yeah.
I saw that.
He hopes it would make a difference.
Um, what'd you want to, uh,
what'd you want to talk about?
I've got another tag that I'm thinking may
need to go into, uh, into the next phase.
Right now, what, what,
what tag needs love that is already
existing and that I'll be able
to support with, uh, Castapod?
Um, that's already existing, like
in one of the existing phases?
Yeah.
Is there anything that's,
I mean, it feels like, uh,
location has not really taken off yet
or it's not understood or, I
mean, it's being used, but, um,
location, you know what?
I almost clipped something that would
have been a perfect thing for location.
And it was from Scientific American.
They have a show that's like a,
I think it's called walking in
national park or something like that.
And it's a walking tour and he'll,
he'll walk around to you a
little bit about where he's
at and he'll stop and let you hear
the nature sounds around you.
That would have been perfect
for chapters and location.
Cause you can, I don't
think some people know that
you can put location
data into its chapters.
Right, right.
No, I don't think that's known of the, we
need more authoring going on for sure.
Yeah.
Uh, we may with, when
it comes to Castapod,
we may just need to bail
and create the feed
from scratch rather than trying to import.
Oh.
Cause we could, we could
just bring in how many feed,
how many items do you
keep or past episodes
do you keep in a feed?
10?
Uh, no agenda.
I keep 10 because, um, it's
just too, I used to put the,
a lot of show notes in there.
The feed was just so huge.
It was costing me an arm and a leg.
And then I met Dave Jones and he
fixed that, um, on podcasting 2.0,
every single one is in the feed.
Oh, that's the whole feed then.
Yeah.
We, we, we, we, it's tough, right?
Mm-hmm.
Can't you just, uh, start the new
feed and then jackknife, uh, yeah,
just jackknife all those items.
You know what I mean, Dave?
It's a technical term.
Don't, don't mess around with me.
Jackknife that shit right in.
Jackknife.
Jackknife the rest of the feed
into whatever's new at the bottom.
Will that work?
I'll just use the jackknife
command in Linux.
Don't you do cat?
Cat.
Cat, cat, pipe, jackknife.
Exactly.
Um, I don't know what
else, I mean, what else,
what else would be
appropriate for our show?
I mean, clearly we're
already using chapters
and transcripts and all
that kind of stuff.
And we don't have location.
We're not really a location-based show.
No, but I, I, I just feel that this should
be the show that supports every tag.
I mean, this is the one,
this is the flagship.
What would our location be?
Uh.
Because it's supposed to be what the,
what the location tag is
supposed to be what the show
is about and not where it's,
not where the hosts live.
Well, that's what you say.
It's what I say.
Yeah.
What if I, I mean, that's,
that's like saying the alternate enclosure
is only for different fidelity rates.
I said, that's what Cridlin says.
Well.
That's what I love about it.
It can be used in different ways.
So what's the location?
You're in Austin.
I'm in, well, no, you're
not in Austin anymore.
You're in, uh, the hill country.
Yeah.
And I'm in Birmingham.
The South.
Yeah.
There you go.
The South.
That's a real big area.
God's country.
Then you just put up one
of those vaccination, uh,
maps and you can see that we live in the
places where the, where it's bad.
Red zone.
Red states that don't vaccinate.
That's where we live.
Um.
Yeah.
Okay.
Well, I don't know.
That's, we could do, we could do that one.
And then there's also, we should
probably put in the podcast.
Well, here's a good person.
I don't have persons.
I don't have that yet.
Oh yeah.
We need that.
Yeah.
We got to eat our own dog food on that.
For sure.
All right.
Anyway, other namespace stuff.
Well, I'm thinking.
Oh, I thought you, I
thought you had new stuff
for phase four that you
wanted to talk about.
Yeah, I do.
Okay.
Uh, so the, the other ones I'm thinking
of are the dynamic content tag.
And this one was initially brought up a long
time ago, I think, but then it was sort
of resurrected in a different form by a
guy who's a developer at Facebook who,
came onto the namespace repo
and said that they really,
for their podcast pages, they really
want to be able to know if the audio
for an, for an item has been dynamic,
has dynamic insertion because they
want to know if they can, um,
trust the timestamps to be consistent.
So, uh, basically what this would be
is just be like a true false flag.
Say is, is, does this item
contain dynamic insertion?
If it does true, if not, or if
the tag is missing, then false.
Wow.
I feel like, like now we
have to create something
in our Bible to fix some stupid shit.
Well, I mean, that's just, that's
my, that's, that's my immediate,
that's my immediate response
is like, okay, so you're inserting
or have ads inserted dynamically.
So now, now that has to be looked at.
I mean, I don't know.
That's like, I mean, that's like
half of RSS is fixing, fixing crap.
Yeah.
Good point.
Fixing crap.
Okay.
Well, uh, Tanner, Tanner Phelps, one of
the things he, circling back on that, he,
he kept claiming, he keeps
using the term that, uh,
what we're doing here
is furthering a frozen
spec with a reference to RSS.
Yes.
RSS is a frozen spec.
The reason it's frozen is because you,
is because all the further
extensions to it need
to happen in namespaces.
Yeah.
So we're not, we're not changing.
Which is what iTunes did by the way.
Yeah.
It was frozen when iTunes did it.
So, yeah, that's, that's something
that everybody needs to understand.
Um, there's that one.
And then there's also the, uh, block tag.
I mean, we can go ahead and put that in.
Mm-hmm.
Um, I actually had a.
Wait, what was blocked for again?
Well, that was the thing where it says, I
don't want my, I don't want my show listed
on these platforms or these
directories or whatever.
And I had a, I actually had a
good example of one this week.
Uh, a guy emailed me and said, Hey,
I, my, my show is showing up on.
Podcast index.
And right.
It was a private feed that he knew wasn't
really private, but it wasn't surfaced.
And he just wanted to say, Hey,
you know, of course we sucked.
I mean, that's, uh, that's not us.
That's our crazy Swede.
Oh yeah.
The Swedish trickler.
He's like, if you've got a
feed out there, it's not safe.
He's going to find it.
I'm going to, if a feed exists anywhere.
It'll be fine.
Um, and so we somehow found it
sucked it in the index and it was a,
it was essentially a duplicate, but
it was a members only duplicate
that he only wanted for his members.
And he was surfacing it through
Patreon or something like that.
And so, you know, he's,
and he even told it.
Yeah.
Like you said, he told us,
he's like, well, you know,
I know this is not the right way
to do this, but that's, you
know, I'm, I understand that,
but can you just take it down for me?
It's, you know, so yeah, sure.
So, so, so it's a block as in what you,
what directory you don't
want it to show up in.
Yeah.
It's like, okay, if I'm
going to live this,
if these platforms are listed in the block
tag, then I'd want them
not to ingest my feed.
And what kind of standard do we set for
the, uh, is that just based on domain name?
Well, uh, yeah, there's going to be like,
there'd have to be some sort of slug
list or something to identify that.
And it would have to be a
community oriented thing.
Okay.
Yeah.
I mean, I don't, like I said before, I
don't, I don't have a problem with it.
The only time I'm going
to have a problem with
it is if somebody starts
using it abusively.
And then at that point, I'm
just going to ignore it.
I'm like, you know, so anyway, that,
that's, that's my feeling on it.
So I don't have a problem putting it in.
I, you know, I think it can be helpful.
And for somebody like, and it's going
to be in a, it's going to be a, um,
on a source sort of level too.
Uh, cause if you, you know, you obviously
got people that you're going to trust.
So you have people like
the hosting companies that
are probably going to be fine, like Buzz
Sprout and these guys and
blueberry and, you know, farce.
I mean, they're, they're going
to be, they're trustworthy.
They're not going to pull any shenanigans.
Then you may have some new actor that
comes in that tries to, you know,
use it to somebody else's
competitive disadvantage.
And for those, I'll just say, well,
I'll continue to honor it
for these other ones, but
for this new guy and who's, you know,
screwing everybody over, I'll just ignore it.
Right.
Hmm.
I wonder, uh, Dave, do you
need to go talk to him?
He's barking up a storm in the background.
I can hear you talking through
it, but I know you hear it.
He's always flipping out.
Yeah.
He's flipping out.
Does he need a moment?
You need to talk to him?
Is it too distracting?
I can go.
No, not for me.
Not for me.
I just, for you, that's fine.
We can, uh, we, we, we, we accept pets,
uh, and children in the boardroom.
There's no problem here.
Yeah.
Let me, uh, let me go,
uh, settle him down.
Okay.
All right.
That's kind of mean, Dave.
You don't have to do that.
He's quiet though, isn't he?
He's real quiet.
He is dead quiet.
Um, we have started,
stopped and started more on this one
episode than we ever have before.
We had a dog stop, a dimmer stop, and,
uh, and now the show's almost over.
Uh, a fuzz, a fuzzy audio interface stop.
Hey, you got any clips you want to play?
I mean, you've got so many here.
I, I, I feel like we should be
doing some of these at least.
Well, the problem is I've
got like three threads of,
of research going on at the same time.
And I keep, like, I've got stacks of stuff
over here that we're not able to get to.
Like one thing I want to talk about at
some point in the future, not today,
is the anti green, uh, excuse me, the,
the, the anti Bitcoin green stuff.
Mm-hmm.
The thermal.
Yeah.
The ESG rating, the, uh.
Uh, but we, we can do
that some other time.
And then, but I've got some stuff on that.
But you want, do you want to play?
I've got another ISO.
Okay.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Sure, sure, sure, sure.
It's a boom what?
Boom what?
I don't know, Dave.
I don't know.
The boost was my favorite.
Boost!
And everyone's finger moves immediately.
It's like a Pavlovian thing.
You're sitting there, you're listening
to this podcast, you're digging it,
all of a sudden you hear.
Boost!
And you know, you just got
to hit the boost button.
I see Martin has been
boosting us a thousand times.
Oh, is he?
He keeps, he's like, eh, but he's
still, he's still not getting the, uh,
he's still not getting
the sats through now.
Oh, he could be sending
us a hundred thousand
sats at a time and we don't even know it.
But it's all my money anyway, so
he's just, he's just giving it back.
This is what I love the
most about our system.
We're all sending money to
each other all day long.
Literally.
Yes.
Yeah, it's true.
I mean, I, I definitely refill, I
refill at least once every week,
maybe 10 days, but yeah.
A response, a responsible
development effort would
create a test net and do all these things
so that you're not using live funds.
We don't do that at all.
No, no, no, no.
That's for pussies, man.
This is, this is real work here.
Yeah.
Only real men and women are allowed
here and we don't mess around.
There's slinging five and 10 bucks
around at a time all the time.
Slinging.
That's right.
Hold on a second.
I have a jingle for that too.
Yeah.
You got the jingle for slinging stuff?
Uh, well, when it comes to, uh, yeah.
Slinging stuff.
Uh, I think this shot collar, 20 inch
blades on the Impala, big baller.
There you go.
That sounds like a MoFax clip.
Totally stolen from MoFax.
Totally.
I like, I liked how, um, Oh, well, you
know what I had to tell, I had to, uh,
we were going
to play this clip back when we were
talking about the Spotify stuff earlier.
There's a clip in here called
Spotify, not my issue.
And I don't know if you've heard this,
but this is sort of the inventor,
so to speak of Spotify's tech.
Oh yes.
I have heard, or I read a
transcript of some of this.
Yeah.
Very interesting.
This is the clip.
Um, if you want to play it now,
so this is, Oh, what is her name?
Jana something who is a music artist
and she's talking, she's asking him to,
uh, consider art and giving artists a one
cent per stream, uh, additional royalty.
Like a bonus for, for starting
up a stream, give him a penny.
Yeah.
And so this was, uh,
this was his response.
Maybe to consider some,
the idea of having a $10 a month
service plus one cent per song
would make people so much more money.
And everybody is really broke.
Well, the artists are broke.
We're not making any
money off of the streams.
And I know that you know this and I,
I'm not trying to put you on the spot.
I'm just saying.
One cent is really not
even that much money.
If you add 2 million times 0.01,
it's, it's still not that much.
And like, if you would just consider.
I'm going to go down this road.
You know that.
Do I go down the entitlement
road now or do I wait a minute?
Well, you know what?
I think that you should
know what you need to do.
Yeah.
What you feel you need to do.
So maybe I should go down the entitlement
road now or should I wait a few minutes?
You want to wait a few minutes?
Maybe take another question.
You guys want to talk about entitlement
now or do we need to talk about it?
Yeah, just go for it.
Hit it.
I don't think it's entitlement to ask
for like normal rates like before.
Normal rates?
No, it's ideas to make it a
win-win situation for all parties.
Okay.
So we should talk about entitlement.
I mean, I have an issue.
Did she just describe what we want to do?
Yes.
Make it a win-win for all parties?
Exactly.
I love it.
This guy, entitlement.
He's being a real jerk.
Oh, totally.
Do you know what the setting of this is?
What was this like?
Some music technology conference
or something like that?
I forgot the name of it, but I'll find it.
All parties.
Okay.
So we should talk about entitlement.
I mean, I have an issue with
Taylor Swift's comments.
I have this issue with, and
we'll call it entitlement.
I mean, I consider myself an
artist because I'm an inventor.
Okay?
Now, I freely give away my patents.
Nothing.
I never collected royalties on anything.
I think that Taylor Swift doesn't
need 0.00001 cent more a stream.
The problem is that Spotify was
created to solve a problem.
The problem was this, piracy
and music distribution.
The problem was to get artists'
music out there to solve a problem.
The problem was not to pay people money.
The problem was to distribute
music, not to give you money.
Okay?
The problem was to distribute music.
You can make the deals with it.
Those aren't our problems.
People would pay one cent a song.
It's literally one cent.
Right?
You understand.
The deal is this, ready?
If the infrastructure doesn't
work, that's not my issue.
This world right now we live in
is built also on entitlement.
Right now, today, everybody here
in this younger world here,
everybody seems to think
about entitlement.
It's not the same.
What do you mean it's not the same?
Entitlement is when you
want more than is normal.
Correct.
We're getting way less than normal.
What do you think is considered a normal?
When you were young, that was a normal.
People made money off of
selling songs that they
worked really hard on
for a really long time.
And now we're basically
giving it away for free.
It's just about compassion.
It's about win-win situations.
The best business deals are win-win.
And you solved a problem,
but now there's another one.
And I'm just saying you're here.
And I'm not trying to attack
whatever you're doing.
But I'm not going to agree with you and say
that musicians are entitled because they
don't want to be flat broke.
Ah, the future of podcasting
on Spotify in a nutshell.
Yeah, that's the attitude.
They are like their owners, which are
mainly, yes, they're a public company,
but all the record companies
got shares pre-IPO.
They're all in it.
And they don't care.
That's what I've always said.
If you're, the key phrase in
there was, if the infrastructure,
and he says infrastructure, but what he
means is like the system of getting paid.
If the infrastructure doesn't
work, that's not my issue.
Yeah.
That's what he said.
And I agree.
And that's why we built
our own infrastructure.
Yeah, because that's the way that Spotify
looks at artists and not just them,
all the platforms, that's the
way they look at artists.
And that's the way they
will look at podcasters.
And I guarantee you, even in
default mode, from my default mode,
Abel Kirby and his band,
the Abel Kirbyites.
Wait, they have a real name, don't they?
That's it, the Abel Kirbyites.
No, no, you're kidding me.
No, no, no, no, no.
I'm just screwing around.
No, it's the Abelcraft.
Oh, that's the podcast, Abelcraft.
Yeah, yeah.
I guarantee you, it'll make a lot
more than one penny per stream.
Oh, yeah.
You know, do a four-minute song, you know,
I'll be sending you some real money,
and I'll be boosting you.
Oh, and it'll be a lot more
than 99 cents on iTunes, too.
And she said it right now.
She said, people are more
than willing to pay for that.
Absolutely.
The problem is Spotify
doesn't know how to chop
that penny in half and take half of it.
If they could do that in real time,
it might be interesting to them.
And I don't fault them for it at all.
That's fine.
But, yeah, man, again, the history
sometimes repeats, but more often than not,
it rhymes, and we've
been around this circle.
We've been through it.
And so that means that it's going to
be tremendously successful, even more.
What do we have, 387
value-enabled podcasts now?
So that's, we need to have
Brian of London on the show.
Yeah, he created like 100 accounts in
video or something that he's going to own.
All the sats belong to me.
Yeah.
I was really curious about that.
I was like, exactly, yeah.
I'm monetizing all of 3Speak myself.
Yeah, well, that's, hey.
Entrepreneurism.
I love him.
But we need to have him on the show
because that is a really cool project,
and I would like to hear him talk
about that and how he's, you know,
sort of how he's building
that whole thing.
Because he's using PodPing for ingestion.
It's just a really cool, cool thing.
The only thing is we just have to
limit, we have to rate limit him.
Yes, because he's going nuts.
No, no, no.
I'm saying like him personally.
We have to rate limit him on the show to
one mention of Hive per minute and no more.
I see.
I wasn't even going to say it.
I was just going to be nice for once.
Well, but while we're talking about
that, how is the uptake of PodPing?
We're still at five hosts.
I got to go give Dan Benjamin some static
because he said he was going to do it,
and he left me out in the cold.
So it's still on his to-do list.
He's probably over there with
David Norman and Ray from Breeze,
and they're all having their own party.
Just like, look at those guys.
What are they doing?
Look at them sweat for nothing.
I mean, we're doing better
than Meghan Markle and Harry.
Only made one episode of a show
with a $25 million contract.
All right.
Well, gosh golly gee.
I think we've got most of the stuff out.
I mean, it was a busy week, but good
stuff, real good stuff happening.
I'm so excited about the comments.
I think that's going to be huge,
and I just love seeing more podcasts
coming online with the value block.
And we've been working real hard.
I should say we, but Eric has been working
really, really hard in that back end,
and the new website is
looking mighty nice.
Really nice.
And then, yeah, so we took on a
chief communications officer,
who I happened to be sleeping with.
Well, I'm sleeping with
my kid's teacher, so.
And so I added her to our signal channel.
It's just the three of us,
and added, and she's like,
last night she went, oh my God.
No wonder you're always
typing on your phone.
You're like a bunch of girls
with all this chatter.
I said, okay, all right, no, no, no,
we're putting up a sign, girls suck,
backwards S, you know, keep out, stay out.
Stay out of the fort.
To be honest, some of the stuff that
we put in there, I'm sure she's like,
what does that even mean?
Probably.
Yeah.
No girls in the tree fort.
No.
But she is going to help us with,
she's going to help us with
getting the message out.
And really, how do we market
what podcasting 2.0 is?
And I believe it'll start with the apps.
I think that's the best way.
And I'd love for podcast index and love
for us to be able to provide, you know,
more marketing than, you
know, we already do.
You know, you're out there tweeting,
I'm out there doing shows.
That's kind of the extent of it.
Speaking of girls in the tree fort,
Stephanie Fuccio wrote a really
good article to her newsletter,
just telling all about the podcast index.
Yes, I saw that.
That was another good article.
Yeah.
And she had gotten some
quotes from people.
I guess she just went and asked for them
from Mark Asquith and Jennifer Neveretti
and the co-founder of Headliner.
It's a good article.
It's at thepodcasthost.com
slash publishing, publishing,
submit your podcast to the podcast index.
So go check that out.
It's really good.
And I appreciate Stephanie.
She's really kind.
That's super.
Yeah.
I just love it when people
get it and then write,
write about it and just keeps the,
the flywheel is already rolling.
We just need to spin it faster.
We need an El Salvador podcast, don't we?
Don't we need one of those
hooked up to value block?
I think we should do a business
trip and go check it out.
Go to the Bitcoin beach,
see what's happening.
I've got a buddy who is
going to El Salvador.
He's going down there.
Yeah.
He's going down there for a, for a job
and he got, he just got the vaccine.
He's already had, he already had
COVID back in, back in December.
And so he was not going to get
the vaccine cause he's like,
I've already had COVID and I've recovered.
Then he had to get it for travel.
Well, he, yeah.
So what he said was when
typically, uh, if you go down,
they do PCR tests coming back.
So it's, it's like, you know, you know,
those are so bad to give
you a false positive.
And so he said that when you go down to
El Salvador and if you PCR test positive
before you get on the plane,
you have to quarantine for a
month before you come back.
Holy crap.
He was like, oh my God, I'm
not, I'm not risking this.
So he got the vaccine and
he said it was awful.
He said it was worse than having COVID
because he had like 103 fever and all this
stuff for like, you know,
for like four days.
He was like, oh, he's fine now.
But he was like, oh, this is awful.
When we went to Mexico,
you had to have a test coming back
to the United States, PCR test.
And so they do that at the
resort we were staying at.
And I said, you know, so what
happens if we test positive?
And he said, don't worry, Mr. Curry,
you're not going to test positive.
Because they then have to
pay for your extended stay.
Oh.
So they have an incentive
to give you a good test.
Yeah.
But don't worry.
It will be fine.
You will not be here next week.
I promise you.
That's awesome.
Well, I can't wait to see
what pops up this week.
Thanks to everybody on podcastindex.social,
everybody contributing,
all ships at sea, everybody
who was getting the word out.
Thank you, Dave.
And thank you, Eric.
And everybody I forgot in my prayers.
I'll tell, who is that?
Andy.
Andy Lehman.
I'll tell the story about the Freedom
Controller URL shortener snafu.
I'll tell that next week.
Ooh.
Okay.
That's not.
Yeah.
Sounds like it's going to be a fun one.
Okay.
No, it's not.
It's not.
Not that fun.
No, it's not that fun.
Okay.
All right, everybody.
That's it for podcasting
2.0 for this week.
We'll be back next week.
We'll do it again on Friday.
Looking forward to see you then.
Thank you all so much.
PodcastIndex.org, PodcastIndex.Social.
See you next week.
Been listening to Podcasting 2.0.
Visit PodcastIndex.org
for more information.
Go podcasting!
Boo!